Reviewer: Marssi Draw
Hi everyone.
Two year ago, my life changed forever.
My wife Kelsey and I
into the world.
is an amazing experience.
Your whole world changes over night.
change immediately.
to process sometimes.
a tremendous amount about being a parent
how to dress your child.
(Laughter)
This was new to me.
I thought this was a good idea.
that it's not a good idea. (Laughter)
so much craziness all at once.
Kelsey and I both work from home,
we run our own businesses.
online for yoga teachers.
I'm an author.
Kelsey's working from home.
and we're trying to make sure
that needs done.
And life is really, really busy.
into this amazing experience,
really kicked in,
like around week eight,
and it was the same thought
internationally,
which is:
free time ever again.
(Laughter)
Somebody said it's true.
It's not exactly true,
in that moment.
disconcerning to me,
because one of the things that I enjoy
is learning new things.
and diving in
learning through trial and error.
at something.
And without this free time,
going to do that ever again.
And so, I'm a big geek,
I want to keep growing.
And so what I've decided to do was,
and go to the bookstore,
and look at what research says about
how we learn and how we learn quickly.
I read a bunch of websites.
And tried to answer this question,
to acquire a new skill?
You know what I found?
10,000 hours!
Anybody ever heard this?
If you want to learn something new,
if you want to be good at it,
to get there.
in website after website.
of reading all of this stuff was like:
No!!
I don't have 10,000 hours.
to learn anything new.
(Laughter)
But that's not true.
a rough order of magnitude,
for five years.
That's a long time.
of learning something new,
close to that amount of time, right?
kinda funky going on here.
and have experiences,
they don't match up.
And what I found, here's the wrinkle:
of expert-level performance.
at Florida State University,
his name is K. Anders Ericsson.
of the 10,00 hour rule.
he studied professional athletes,
chess grand masters.
in ultra-high performing fields.
how long does it take
of those kinds of fields.
the more deliberate practice,
that those individuals spend
of whatever it is that they do,
the better you get.
of their fields
put in around 10,000 hours of practice.
of telephone a little bit earlier.
Here's what happened:
of Malcolm Gladwell
"Outliers: The Story of Success",
was the 10,000 hour rule.
and you will do extremely well,
you will reach the top of your field.
So, the message,
what Dr. Ericsson was actually saying is,
at the top of an ultra competitive field
that's what that means.
ever since Outliers came out,
reached the top of best seller lists,
stayed there for three solid months.
was everywhere.
started to be played.
to reach the top of an ultra competitive field,
to become an expert at something,
which became,
good at something,
to learn something.
it takes 10,000 hours to learn something,
It's not true.
So, what the research actually says --
at the CSU library
'cause I'm a geek.
at the studies of skill acquisition,
a graph like this.
whether they're studying a motor skill,
or a mental skill,
that they can time.
'Cause you can quantify that, right?
a little task,
physical arrangement,
learning a little mental trick,
takes to complete the skill.
when you start --
a task, it took them a really long time,
and they were horrible.
they get better and better and better.
is really, really efficient.
with just a little bit of practice.
Now, what's interesting to note is that,
for ourselves,
right?
whatever good happens to mean.
to how good you are,
his famous and widely known,
this is the learning curve.
is when you start,
and you know it, right?
(Laughter)
you get really good, really quick.
is really fast.
you reach a plateau,
become much harder to get,
they take more time to get.
I want that, right?
from starting something
and knowing it
to being reasonably good?
as possible.
So, how long does that take?
Here's what my research says: 20 hours.
You can go from knowing nothing
about any skill that you can think of.
Want to learn how to draw?
flaming chainsaws?
(Laughter)
deliberate practice into that thing,
you will be astounded.
Astounded at how good you are.
20 hours is doable,
for about a month.
here and there.
20 hours isn't that hard to accumulate.
Now, there's a method to doing this.
fiddling around for about 20 hours
and expect these massive improvements.
There's a way to practice intelligently.
There's a way to practice efficiently,
those 20 hours
that you possibly can.
it applies to anything:
The first is to deconstruct the skill.
to be able to do when you're done,
and break it down into smaller pieces.
that we think of as skills
that require all sorts of different things.
The more you can break apart the skill,
the more you're able to decide,
that would actually help me
get to what I want?
And then you can practice those first.
the most important things first,
your performance
in the least amount of time possible.
to self correct.
about what it is you're trying to learn.
could be courses, could be anything.
to procrastinate on practice.
I know I do this, right?
like,
how to program a computer
when I complete these 20 books".
No. That's procrastination.
is learn just enough
that you can actually practice
as you practice.
a way of getting better
when you're making a mistake
a little different.
to practice.
Distractions, television, internet.
that get in the way
and doing the work.
just a little bit of willpower
are keeping you from practicing,
sit down and practice, right?
for at least 20 hours.
a frustration barrier.
and-knowing-it part?
We don't like to feel stupid.
actually sitting down and doing the work.
whatever it is that you want to do
for at least 20 hours,
that initial frustration barrier
to actually reap the rewards.
That's it! It's not rocket science.
you can use to learn anything.
about in theory,
in practice.
to learn how to do for a long time
is play the ukulele.
Jake Shimabukuro's TEDTalk
and makes it sound like --
he's like a ukulele god.
It's amazing.
"That is so cool!"
I would really like to learn how to play.
that to test this theory
into practicing ukulele
and see where it got.
about playing the ukulele is,
you have to have one, right?
-- My lovely assistant?
(Laughter)
I think I need the chord here.
it's an electric ukulele. (Laughter)
Yeah.
like the first couple hours of anything.
that you are using to practice.
they're available.
with strings attached.
how to put those on.
Like, that's kind of important, right?
learning how to make sure
that need to be done
get done, right?
ready to actually start practicing
and songbooks for how to play songs.
play more than one string at a time,
so you can play chords, that's cool,
yay you. (Laughter)
And when I started looking at songs,
that had like hundreds of chords.
"Wow, that's intimidating".
But when you look at the actual songs,
over and over, right?
is kind of like doing anything,
that are really important
all the time.
you'll use four, maybe five chords,
and that's it, that's the song.
as long as you know the four or the five.
So, while I was doing my research,
of pop songs
(Whistles)
-- Somebody knows it. --
is that you can learn,
any pop song of the past five decades,
if you know four chords,
and those chords are G, D, Em and C.
every pop song ever, right?
So I thought, this is cool!
every pop song ever. (Laughter)
I decided to learn,
share it with you. Ready?
Alright.
(Music)
Just a small town girl,
living in a lonely world,
going anywhere.
(Laughter)
that you found a girl,
that you're married now.
(Laughter)
I see you, I feel you,
It cannot wait, I'm yours.
we did amazing things.
I'd go wherever you will --
(Laughter)
I can't live with or without you.
When I find myself --
mother Mary comes to me,
No woman, no cry.
Yeah mama, this surely is a dream.
(Laughter)
camped by a billabong.
but here's my number, so call me
oppan gangnam style. (Laughter)
It's time to say goodbye.
comes from some other beginning's end.
(Applause)
Thank you, thank you.
(Laughter)
And I have a secret to share with you.
So, by playing that song for you,
of practicing the ukulele.
Thank you.
anything that you can think of,
what do you want to do.
something new is not intellectual,
a bunch of little tips or tricks or things.
We're scared.
Feeling stupid doesn't feel good,
anything new
you feel really stupid.
it's emotional.
But put 20 hours into anything.
What do you want to learn?
Want to learn how to cook?
Want to learn how to draw?
What lights you up?
It only takes 20 hours.
Have fun.
(Applause)